{"tossups": [{"question": "Six years after this bill passed, its Section 13A was examined in the case<em> New Negro Alliance v.</em> <em>Sanitary Grocery Co</em>. Section 2 of this bill acknowledged how the central group it was meant for had been\u201ccommonly helpless to exercise actual liberty.\u201d The namesakes of this anti-injunction bill were a Nebraska senator who also names the first dam constructed by the Tennessee Valley Authority and a New York representative who served as Mayor of New York from 1934-45. For the point, name this 1932 pro-union bill that outlawed yellow dog contracts.", "answer": "<b> Norris-La Guardia</b> Act (accept<b> Anti-Injunction</b> Bill before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "For the point, name this country that gained its independence after the breakup of Yugoslavia and established its capital at Zagreb.", "answer": "<b> Croatia</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Before this battle, the winner set fire to the grass; combined with the lack of water in the Springs of Turan, this made the losing side desperately thirsty. After the battle, the winner was given an alcoholic drink as a symbol that he would be spared, which he misinterpreted by disgustedly passing the glass to his ally, Reynald of Chatillon. Five months after this battle, Baldwin IV routed the winner of this battle at Montgisard. This battle, which was named for an extinct volcano that had two peaks, allowed its winner to recapture Jerusalem later that year. For the point, name this 1187 battle where Saladin crushed the crusaders.", "answer": "Battle of (the Horns of)<b> Hattin</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This document, whose creation was fueled by anger arising from the<em> Black Warrior</em> Affair, noted that a certain region \u201cbelongs naturally to that great family of states of which the Union is the Providential Nursery.\u201d William Marcy urged for the creation of this document, which was prepared by three men, including John Mason. Young America member Pierre Soul\u00b4e participated in the writing of this document, named for a Belgium city. Franklin Pierce\u2019s administration was damaged by, for the point, what 1854 document that threatened U.S. annexation of Cuba?", "answer": "<b> Ostend</b> Manifesto (or<b> Ostend</b> Circular) Page 1", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Suetonius relates that, after this man noticed that he had not helped anyone that day, he lamented\u201cFriends, I have lost a day.\u201d This man commanded the Fifteenth Legion during the Siege of Yodfat, where he served under his father. An Amazon carried this man in a four-horsed chariot in a monument that commemorates his success at the Siege of Jerusalem. Mount Vesuvius erupted during the reign of this man, whose namesake arch was built two years after he completed the Colosseum. For the point, name this Flavian emperor who succeeded his father Vespasian.", "answer": "<b> Titus</b> Flavius Caesar Vespasianus Augustus", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "This man began one conflict after a failed assassination of the ambassador Argov, a minister to the United Kingdom; that war allowed him to install a friendly government led by Bachir Gemayel. This man led the Herut party, which comprised many members of his former Irgun militia. This man launched Operation Opera, bombing the Osirak reactor to cripple Iraq\u2019s nuclear capabilities. One of this man\u2019s peaceful gestures involved the return of the Sinai to Anwar Sadat. For the point, name this founder of the Likud Party, the Israeli signatory of the Camp David Accords.", "answer": "Menachem<b> Begin</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This man\u2019s first act as governor was to execute Suleiman Zobeir to end the slave trade. A famous depiction of this man\u2019s final battle shows him staring at his watch as he is about to be speared. This man rose to prominence after succeeding Frederick Ward as head of the Ever Victorious Army. William Gladstone\u2019s government fell after failing to rescue this man from a Mahdist rebellion in the Sudan. For the point, name this British army general, known as \u201cChinese\u201d for his role in the Taiping Rebellion.", "answer": "Charles George \u201cChinese\u201d<b> Gordon</b> Page 2", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "A famous resident of this city, who wrote<em> In Praise</em> <em>of Folly</em>, is commemorated as the namesake of a bridge that crosses the New Meuse River. For the point, name this largest port in Europe and second-most populous Dutch city, the birthplace of the philosopher Erasmus.", "answer": "<b> Rotterdam</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "James Townsley claimed he was forced to participate in this event, which resulted in the deaths of three members of the Doyle family. Despite being the target of this event, \u201cDutch Henry\u201d Sherman was spared because he was not home. The destruction of the offices of the<em> Herald of Freedom</em> and the Free State Hotel precipitated this event. The sacking of Lawrence was the impetus of, for the point, what retaliatory 1856 massacre in Kansas led by John Brown?", "answer": "<b> Pottawatomie</b> Massacre (prompt on Bleeding Kansas)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "A movement named for its leaders\u2019 shoes inspired one side\u2019s goals during this conflict, which included the Battle of Frankenhausen. After a leader of this uprising forced the Count of Helfenstein to run the gauntlet, he was replaced by a knight who had a iron prosthetic hand, Gotz von Berlichingen. During this conflict, which began when its perpetrators refused to collect snail shells, the Swabian League was presented with the<em> Twelve Articles</em>. Supporters of this war were condemned as \u201cmurderous, thieving hordes\u201d by Martin Luther. For the point, name this 1524 war fought against the Holy Roman Empire by namesake agricultural laborers.", "answer": "German<b> Peasants\u2019</b> War (or Revolt; accept any description of a war involving German <b>peasants</b>; accept<b> Muntzer</b>\u2019s Revolt; prompt on \u201cPeasants\u2019 War\u201d and similar partial answers)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This event\u2019s perpetrators rose to prominence after attacking the Senluo Temple, causing its support to peak. Supporters of this event perpetrated the Juye Incident, in which missionary Richard Henle was murdered. This event included the siege of the Legations, which ended only when the Eight Nation Alliance was deployed. The New Policies were enacted by the Qing [ching] to address their failures during, for the point, what anti-foreigner rebellion that began in 1899 and was led by the Righteous and Harmonious Fists in China?", "answer": "<b> Boxer</b> Rebellion (accept<b> Yihetuan</b> Movement; accept<b> Quan Luan</b> Rebellion; accept the movement of<b> Righteous and Harmonious Fists</b> before mentioned) Page 3", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This politician\u2019s party frantically nominated four different candidates after this man withdrew from an election after the death of his daughter Anne. The Alabama Letter was issued by this man to explain his stance on the annexation of Texas. In 1832, this man lost to Andrew Jackson as a member of the National Republican Party, which then merged with other parties to create the Whigs. This man was accused of striking a \u201ccorrupt bargain\u201d with John Quincy Adams that led to him becoming Secretary of State. For the point, name this Kentucky politician labeled the \u201cGreat Compromiser.\u201d", "answer": "Henry<b> Clay</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This speech quoted Bill Clinton\u2019s claim that its speaker was \u201cjust managing the government\u201d instead of leading the nation. Patrick Caddell attributed much of this speech\u2019s failure to the ensuing firing of Joseph Califano and James Schlesinger. The book<em> What the Heck Are You Up to, Mr. President</em> chronicles events surrounding this speech, whose speaker sequestered himself in Camp David for ten days prior to it. The \u201cvery heart and soul and spirit of our national will\u201d was the subject of an \u201cinvisible threat\u201d according to, for the point, what 1979 speech by Jimmy Carter, delivered during the energy crisis to a downtrodden country?", "answer": "<b> Malaise</b> speech (accept<b> Crisis of Confidence</b> speech) Page 4", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This man\u2019s victory at Petrovardin allowed him to pass the Treaty of Passarowitz over his enemies. This man mentored a young Frederick the Great at the Battle of Phillipsburg, one of his last battles in the War of Polish Succession. This man expelled the Ottomans from central Europe at Zenta, and his alliance with the Duke of Marlborough helped win the Battles of Blenheim and Malplaquet. For the point, name this Hapsburg prince, an Imperial commander during the War of the Spanish Succession.", "answer": "<b> Eugene of Savoy</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "In 1999, this team fired manager Tim Johnson after just one winning season after reports surfaced that he\u2019d lied about his Vietnam War service. This team hired Cito Gaston as manager twice and John Gibbons as manager twice; Gaston won back-to-back World Series with this team in 1992 and 93, while Gibbons was unable to take Josh Donaldson and Jose Bautista past the ALCS. Rogers Communications purchased this team in 2000 and also owns its stadium, the former SkyDome, which sits underneath the CN Tower. For the point, name this Major League Baseball team, the only Canadian team to win a World Series.", "answer": "<b> Toronto Blue Jays</b> (accept either or both names; prompt on Jays)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "In one opinion, this justice wrote that presidential power \u201cmust stem either from an act of Congress or from the Constitution itself.\u201d In his dissent in<em> Adamson v. California</em>, this justice argued for a complete application of the Bill of Rights to the states. This author of the majority opinion in the<em> Youngstown</em> case was the first justice appointed to the Supreme Court by FDR. For the point, name this textualist Supreme Court justice and Senator from Alabama who often supported civil rights, despite a past membership with the KKK.", "answer": "Hugo LaFayette<b> Black</b> Page 5", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A saint from this country wrote \u201cThe Dark Night of the Soul,\u201d and another saint from this country wrote \u201cThe Interior Castle.\u201d The Ladino language originates from the Sephardic Jewish community originally of this country. In this home country of St. John of the Cross and St. Teresa of \u00b4Avila, pilgrims follow the Way of St. James to the cathedral of Santiago de Compostela. For the point, name this country where the Sagrada Familia basilica has been under construction for over 100 years in Barcelona.", "answer": "<b> Spain</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "Walter Duranty was awarded a Pulitzer Prize for his reporting on this initiative, which began after an earlier initiative was abandoned in the Great Turn. A square in Yekaterinburg is named after this initiative, one of whose goals was the creation of the Dnieper Dam. The Holodomor famine may have been a result of this initiative, which aimed for a 200% increase in iron production and a 110% rise in coal production. For the point, name this economic initiative organized by Stalin from 1928 to 1933.", "answer": "the USSR\u2019s<b> first Five Year Plan</b> (prompt on \u201cFive Year Plan(s)\u201d)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "As a result of this program, Elmer \u201cGeronimo\u201d Pratt was jailed for 27 years. William Sullivan was in charge of this program, which had the goal of being able to \u201cPrevent the Rise of a Messiah.\u201d One venture of this program included the phrase \u201cYou Are Done\u201d as part of a letter encouraging suicide. This program noted that Stokely Carmichael had \u201cthe necessary charisma to be a real threat.\u201d Following the 1963 March on Washington, J. Edgar Hoover marked Martin Luther King to be investigated by, for the point, what partially-illegal FBI initiative?", "answer": "<b> COINTELPRO</b> (accept<b> Counter Intelligence Program</b>; prompt on FBI before mentioned; prompt on descriptions of the FBI/J. Edgar Hoover\u2019s campaign against the Black Panthers and/or Martin Luther King)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This war was briefly halted by the Memorandum of Understanding, but continued until one side was able to control the A9 highway. During this war, one side launched Operation Unceasing Waves I, II, and III as the capital of Kilinochchi changed hands multiple times. One side initiated this conflict after ambushing army patrol Four Four Bravo and lost support after a suicide attack killed foreign leader Rajiv Gandhi. A desire to create the state of Eelam led to, for the point, what war that lasted from 1983 to 2009, in which the Tamil Tigers fought against government forces on an island in the Indian Ocean?", "answer": "<b> Sri Lanka</b>n<b> Civil</b> War (prompt on partial answers) Page 6", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This region is the origin of the Chod ritual, where practitioners attempt to \u201ccut through the ego\u201dthrough symbolic actions like offering themselves up to be eaten. People from this region inherited, from the native Bon religion, the practices of spinning prayer wheels and flying colorful prayer flags. Vajrayana Buddhists from this region are divided into \u201cRed Hat\u201d and \u201cYellow Hat\u201d lineages. For the point, name this region controlled by China since the 50s, whose Buddhists are led by the Dalai Lama in exile.", "answer": "<b> Tibet</b> (prompt on China before mentioned)", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {"question": "This ruler\u2019s last battle featured the suicide of Poenius Posthumus to atone for cowardice. This ruler was able to gain the support of the Trinovantes after a heavy temple tax was levied on civilians. Suetonius\u2019travels to Anglesey presented an opportunity to this ruler, who took action after the will of Prasutagus was ignored. The Ninth Legion was destroyed by this ruler during the sack of Camulodunum, but she was eventually defeated at the battle of Watling Street near Londinium. For the point, name this Iceni queen who launched a 60 AD revolt in Britain.", "answer": "<b> Boudicca</b> (or<b> Boadicea</b>; accept<b> Buddug</b>)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "These places were the subject of<em> Minersville v. Gobitis</em> and<em> West Virginia v. Barnette</em>, which dealt with the rights of Jehovah\u2019s Witnesses in them. A sexually explicit speech made in one of these locations was the center of<em> Bethel v. Fraser</em>. The wearing of black armbands in these places was the focus of<em> Tinker</em> <em>v. Des Moines</em>, in which Abe Fortas declared that \u201crights do not end at\u201d these places\u2019 \u201cdoor\u201d.<em> Abingdon</em> <em>v. Schempp</em> banned sponsored Bible reading in, for the point, what institutions whose desegregation was the center of<em> Brown v. Board of Education</em>?", "answer": "public<b> school</b>s", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Concessions like Guangzhouwan and parts of Tianjin were located in, for the point, what country where the British colonized the Pearl River\u2019s region of Hong Kong?", "answer": "People\u2019s Republic of<b> China</b> (accept Republic of<b> China</b>; do not accept Taiwan) Page 7", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "At this location, a general\u2019s victory at Thoroughfare Gap allowed two armies to link up and force the withdrawal of John Pope. Troop movements were covertly recorded by Rose Greenhow at this location. A commander successfully defended Henry House Hill at this location, prompting his comrade Barnard Bee to declare, \u201cthere [he is], standing like a stone wall.\u201d Joseph Johnston\u2019s arrival allowed P.G.T. Beauregard to force Irvin McDowell from this Virginia location, where civilians had gathered to picnic and supposedly watch the end of a brief rebellion. For the point, name the location of the first major land battle of the Civil War.", "answer": "<b> Bull Run</b> or<b> Manassas</b> (prompt on Virginia before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "After this man recovered from an injury sustained in a bath, he was allowed to \u201crule,\u201d even though he had already been removed from power. During World War II, this leader\u2019s ambassador Carlos Garrido saved Jews in Hungary. The Tarrafal \u201ccamp of the slow death\u201d was established by this ruler, who was targeted in a bombing by Em\u00b4\u0131dio Santana. This leader used Gilberto Freye\u2019s idea of Lusotropicalism and was succeeded by Marcelo Caetano. The Carnation Revolution ousted, for the point, what dictator of the Estado Novo in Portugal?", "answer": "Antonio de Oliveira<b> Salazar</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Quintus Hortensius opposed this man during an event involving a corrupt governor of Sicily. A work framed as a three day long debate primarily focuses on Scipio Aemilianus and argues that pragmatic statesmanship is superior to political theory. Quintillian once claimed that this author of<em> De Re Publica</em> had a name synonymous with \u201celoquence itself.\u201d For the point, name this famous Roman orator of the<em> Philippics</em>.", "answer": "Marcus Tullius<b> Cicero</b>", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "One man was elected to this post with the help of the Lincoln-Roosevelt League and championed an Alien Land Law of 1913. Frank Merriam was challenged by Raymond Haight for this position and beat a man who ran under the EPIC platform. In 1934, Upton Sinclair ran for this position, which Hiram Johnson held prior to becoming Theodore Roosevelt\u2019s running mate in 1912. In 1962, Richard Nixon declared \u201cyou don\u2019t have Nixon to kick around any more\u201d after losing an election to Pat Brown for this office. For the point, name this statewide once held by Arnold Schwarzenegger and currently held by Gavin Newsom.", "answer": "<b> Governor</b> of<b> California</b> (prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In his youth, this leader commanded forces as a lieutenant general at the Battle of Boquer\u00b4on, and distinguished himself in military service to Higinio Mor\u00b4\u0131nigo. This man rose to power by overthrowing Federico Ch\u00b4avez, and in turn was overthrown by his longtime confidant, Andr\u00b4es Rodr\u00b4\u0131guez. As President, this man\u2019s regime sheltered Josef Mengele and committed numerous human rights violations led by Pastor Coronel. For the point, name this longtime leader of the Colorado Party who ruled Paraguay from 1954 to 1989.", "answer": "Alfredo<b> Stroessner</b> Matiauda Page 8", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This man reclaimed his throne after his troops were victorious in the Rout of Winchester. His forces successfully repulsed an invasion from David of Scotland at the battle of the Standard. After William Adelin was killed aboard the White Ship disaster, this man took control of the country. He agreed to sign the Treaty of Wallingford to end his feud with empress Matilda and confirm Henry II as his successor. For the point, identify this English king who ruled during the Anarchy, a member of the house of Blois.", "answer": "<b> Stephen</b> of Blois", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This artist invoked \u201cthe Spirit of God\u201d and \u201cthe Spirit of the Ancestors\u201d in \u201cA Song for Assata\u201dShakur, who was tortured by police after a 1973 shootout. A James Brown speech is sampled, and Stevie Wonder sings \u201cWe are rewriting the black American story,\u201d on the title track of this artist\u2019s 2016 album, <em>Black America Again</em>. This rapper played James Bevel in the 2014 film<em> Selma</em> and joined John Legend on its Oscar-winning song, \u201cGlory.\u201d \u201cThe Light\u201d is by, for the point, what Chicago-based actor and rapper?", "answer": "<b> Common</b> (accept Lonnie<b> Lynn</b>)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "This man regained a post by having a tall girl named Phye dress as a goddess and accompany him as he entered the city. This man refused to marry the daughter of Megacles [mega-kleez], causing a rivalry between the two. One of this man\u2019s sons was killed by Harmodius and Aristogeiton, who were collectively called the \u201ctyrannicides.\u201d This brother-in-law of Cleisthenes [klyce-then-eez] and father of Hippias and Hipparchus strengthened the olive trade and focused on economic growth. For the point, name this sixth century BC tyrant of Athens.", "answer": "<b> Peisistratos</b> (accept<b> Pisistratus</b>)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "This thinker organized formal systems in a ranking from \u201crecursively enumerable\u201d to \u201ccontext free\u201dand \u201cregular\u201d in his namesake hierarchy. This thinker argued that American mass media controls public opinion to support its governmental system in a book he co-wrote called<em> Manufacturing Consent</em>. This activist against the Vietnam War used the phrase \u201ccolorless green ideas sleep furiously\u201d in his landmark book<em> Syntactic Structures</em>. For the point, name this MIT professor and originator of universal grammar theory, the founder of modern linguistics.", "answer": "(Avram) Noam<b> Chomsky</b>", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Linguistics"}, {"question": "Some of the earliest American projects created with the terms of this agreement taken into account were the<em> Pensacola</em> and<em> Salt Lake City</em>. One side in this agreement allowed another to build projects similar to the<em> Mutsu</em>, which had been partly funded by donations from children. This agreement that called for 10,000 ton displacement limits on cruisers and submarines. This agreement was followed up by a similar 1930 treaty, signed in London. For the point, name this treaty that set international sea power restrictions.", "answer": "<b> Washington</b> Naval Treaty (accept<b> Nine-Power</b> Treaty) Page 10", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Edouard Naville excavated the capital of these peoples at the modern town of Tell-el-Daba, whose kings included Khamudi. Seqenenre Tao fought these people\u2019s leader Apophis. This people\u2019s capital Avaris was attacked by Kamose and Ahmose, and their appearance was posited to be part of the Exodus by the Egyptian historian Manetho. The Second Intermediate Period began after an invasion of these people, which took place four centuries before the Sea Peoples\u2019 invasion. The term \u201cShepherd Kings\u201d has often been used to describe, for the point, what group that conquered Ancient Egypt and ended the Middle Kingdom?", "answer": "<b> Hyksos</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "Eulji Mundeok defeated this dynasty when it tried to attack Pyongyang. This dynasty\u2019s ruler Yangdi invaded Vietnam, and is accused of killing the founder of this dynasty, Emperor Wen. The Battle of the Salsu River was a major defeat for this dynasty, which completed construction on a waterway connecting Hangzhou to Beijing. For the point, name this dynasty that fought a series of wars against the Goguryeo Dynasty of Korea, built the Grand Canal, and was succeeded by the Tang in 618 AD.", "answer": "<b> Sui</b> Dynasty", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This king asked Pope Celestine III to annul his first marriage and later married Agnes of Merania, which led to his country being placed under interdict. The chronicler Rigord gave this man his nickname. This king insisted that a dowry should be returned to him in conferences with Henry II under an elm tree at Gisors. This king, who married Ingebourg of Denmark, traveled with Frederick Barbarossa and Richard I in the Third Crusade and defeated Otto IV and John I at the Battle of Bouvines. For the point, name this French king known as Augustus.", "answer": "<b> Philip II</b> Augustus of France", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Silas Soule was thought to have been murdered for his testimony about this event, which led a man named Hook Nose to lead revenge attacks on cities like Julesburg. The Dog Soldiers were absent at this event, which was partly caused by one side\u2019s refusal to relocate from Fort Lyon. John Chivington gave the orders to conduct this event, for which John Hickenlooper officially apologized on its 150th anniversary. Black Kettle\u2019s Cheyenne followers and the Arapaho were targeted in, for the point, what notorious 1864 massacre of Native Americans in the Colorado Territory?", "answer": "<b> Sand Creek</b> Massacre Page 11", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The defeated challenger in this state\u2019s 2014 senatorial election in 2014 was an independent who Joe Biden claimed would caucus with the Democrats; that man was Greg Orman. A senator from this state served as Gerald Ford\u2019s vice presidential nominee in 1976 and selected Jack Kemp as his own running mate in 1996. That man\u2019s successor in the Senate was widely criticized while serving as this state\u2019s governor for turning down an HHS grant to set up an Obamacare exchange in his state and sharply cutting this state\u2019s taxes in a \u201cred state experiment.\u201d For the point, name this home state of Bob Dole and Sam Brownback.", "answer": "<b> Kansas</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "James Iredell gave the lone dissenting opinion in this case, in which he cited common law definitions of sovereignty and asked \u201cdo the people of the United States form a nation?\u201d The plaintiff in this case represented Robert Farquhar, who claimed to have not been reimbursed for assisting the defendant during the Revolutionary War. This court case prompted the 1795 passage of the Eleventh Amendment. For the point, name this case overseen by John Jay which dealt with whether citizens could sue a state.", "answer": "<b> Chisholm</b> v. Georgia", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In one part of this work, its probable commissioner is shown saying grace as chicken is being skewered over an open fire; another portion of this work shows two men being dragged out of quicksand. The final caption of this work, which says that one group \u201cis fleeing,\u201d is thought to be false. A poem by the Bishop of Dol made one of the earliest references to this work, which was commissioned by either Matilda of Flanders or Bishop Odo. Halley\u2019s Comet appears in, for the point, what embroidery depicting the Norman Conquest?", "answer": "<b> Bayeux Tapestry</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This piece was inspired after its composer heard a tune being sung by the 6th Wisconsin Volunteer Infantry. Its chorus may have developed from an earlier song called \u201cCanaan\u2019s Happy Shore,\u201d and that chorus echoes \u201cGlory, glory hallelujah\u201d thrice. Written by Julia Ward Howe and set to the music of \u201cJohn Brown\u2019s Body,\u201d it opens with the refrain, \u201cMine eyes have seen the glory / of the coming of the Lord.\u201dFor the point, name this religious-patriotic song popularized during the Civil War.", "answer": "The<b> Battle Hymn of the Republic</b> Page 12", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "An author from this country wrote a work in which Janet Hayakawa sets the techie John up with his girlfriend, Liz, in a work inspired by<em> Eugene Onegin</em>. The twins Estha and Rahel are separated for decades in a Booker Prize-winning novel set in this country.<em> The Golden Gate</em> and<em> The God of Small Things</em> are set in this country, the home of an author who adopted the pseudonym \u201cJoseph Anton\u201d after a fatwa was issued against his novel<em> Satanic Verses</em>. For the point, name this home country of Arundhati Roy, Vikram Seth, and Salman Rushdie.", "answer": "<b> India</b>", "metadata": "Literature - World Literature - Long Fiction"}, {}, {"question": "This ruler survived assassination from a 25 barreled gun, an \u201cinfernal machine\u201d built by Giuseppe Fieschi. Popular discontent against this ruler grew after Francois Guizot prevented enemies of the Doctrinaires from meeting. This leader of the Orleanists was opposed by the Legitimist faction, which sought to restore the Bourbon monarchy. This man took power after Charles X was forced to abdicate. For the point, name this monarch who ruled over the July Monarchy in France.", "answer": "<b> Louis Philippe</b> I", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "Richard Talbot led one side\u2019s army in this battle, while the other side\u2019s army suffered in the Dundalk camp. The loser of this battle finally stopped fighting after the Treaty of Limerick. George Walker was killed in this battle near Oldbridge, where the Blue Guards held off cavalry attacks. Two days before this battle, Anglo-Dutch forces lost to the Comte de Tourville at the Battle of Beachy Head. The Orange Institution commemorates this battle with yearly parades on The Twelth. For the point, name this battle in the Williamite War in Ireland, where William III defeated James II\u2019s forces on a namesake river.", "answer": "Battle of the<b> Boyne</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Many of this city\u2019s inscriptions were illegally removed by Harald Wagner. Another inscription in this city tells of Spearthrower Owl, who reigned for sixty years as king. The<em> Ciudadela</em> of this city contains a pyramid filled with snake-heads at each level, leading archaeologists to name it after a later deity, Quetzalcoatl. The Temple of the Sun is located along this city\u2019s Avenue of the Dead. For the point, name this pre-Columbian Mexican city whose heyday preceded that of the Aztec Empire.", "answer": "<b> Teotihuacan</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "As a youth, this man replied \u201cit\u2019s my medicine\u201d when he was caught drinking gin. Jesse Anderson and this man were beaten to death on work duty by Christopher Scarver. Steven Hicks was the first victim of this man, who committed that murder with a 10 pound dumbbell. Born in West Allis, this man\u2019s frequent eating of his victims led him to be nicknamed the \u201cMilwaukee Cannibal.\u201d This man\u2019s crimes often began by luring young men into his apartment before sedating and killing them. For the point, name this serial killer who killed 17 people in the 1980s.", "answer": "Jeffrey Lionel<b> Dahmer</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "To disprove Georges Urbain\u2019s claim that element 72 was a rare-earth metal, this man hired George de Hevesy and Dick Coster to isolate hafnium from zirconium ores. He\u2019s not Rutherford, but a model named for this man is a violation of the Heisenberg Uncertainty Principle because it is impossible to know both a particle\u2019s radius and momentum at the same time. This man applied Planck\u2019s theory of quantization to electronic transmissions and used the Rydberg formula to calculate \u201callowable\u201d energy levels for a hydrogen atom. For the point, name this Danish physicist.", "answer": "Niels<b> Bohr</b>", "metadata": "Science - Physics"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "The opening of this structure was known as the \u201cPeople\u2019s Day\u201d and, much to the ire of the Irish, was chosen on the date of Queen Victoria\u2019s birthday. The Master Mechanic of this structure, E.F. Farrington, was the first person to travel across this structure by wire. \u201cCaisson disease\u201d afflicted workers on this structure who were affected by rapid depressurization. After the death of the original designer of this structure, leadership passed to that man\u2019s 32-year old son; Washington Roebling. For the point, name this structure, completed in 1883, that connects two New York City boroughs and is named for one of them.", "answer": "<b> Brooklyn Bridge</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "An 18th century religious figure in this kingdom, Dona Beatriz, claimed to be an incarnation of St. Anthony. This kingdom, which profited from the sale of raffia cloth, was ruled by kings called manis; one such king was Nzinga a Mvemba, who became known as Afonso I upon his conversion to Christianity. This kingdom was administered from towns called mbanzas, the largest of which shared its name with this kingdom. In 1914, Portugal abolished the monarchy of, for the point, what kingdom that flourished from the 14th century along a namesake river in central Africa?", "answer": "Kingdom of<b> Kongo</b> Page 15", "metadata": "History - World History"}], "bonuses": []}